<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xml:lang="en-us">
	<title>Comments on Creating Shared Language and Shared Artifacts</title>
	<subtitle>[brief summary of longer post] The average native English language speaker uses in the realm of 12,000 to 20,000 words, whereas a college graduate would use 20-25,000 words…Every time a new group of people meet together — whether in a team, in a marketplace, or in a community — one of the first activities they must do together is create a shared language…They do this in order to communicate more effectively together, to put a context on the words that they have in common, to construct a shared understanding in their minds based both on available information and their individual diversity of experience…Without a shared language there will be no clarity on mutual goals — whether it involves working together, transacting a trade, or creating something…However, some facilitators have learned that one of the best ways to help a group form a shared language is by having the group create together a shared artifact…It allows the individuals participating to ask the questions: &quot;Is this what you mean when you are talking about this?..an important factor in shared artifacts — if the shared artifact is not constrained then it will be too large or complex for the group to reach some measure of completion…Often there are differences in status, purpose, or perspective that can get in the way of group formation, but a focus on a common task of the creation of a neutral shared artifact allows those issues to come later as the participants develop the trust and shared language required to talk about those tough issues.…The conjoined social networks in the blogosphere — via Facebook, Twitter, or the attendee-focused Unconference — cause new terminology and new language to form ever faster…Or is there just not enough space for it within the tightly constrained social artifacts of the internet?…These are questions that we as social software technologists need to address as the future of the internet increasingly becomes the present of our social groupings.</subtitle>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" title="Comments on Creating Shared Language and Shared Artifacts" href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2009/09/creating-shared-language-and-shared-artiifacts/comments/atom.xml" />
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating Shared Language and Shared Artifacts" href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2009/09/creating-shared-language-and-shared-artiifacts.html"/>
	<generator uri="http://www.typepad.com/">TypePad</generator>
	<xhtml:meta xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="robots" content="noindex" />
	<updated>2009-09-17T07:03:55Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>ChristopherA</name>
		<uri>http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2009/09/creating-shared-language-and-shared-artiifacts/comments/atom.xml/</id>
    
		<entry>
			<title>Dave Carter commented on &#39;Creating Shared Language and Shared Artifacts&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shared artifacts are also known as models; the best form of understanding of business that I have found yet is..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2009/09/creating-shared-language-and-shared-artiifacts.html?cid=6a00d8341d8bc053ef014e88415ceb970d#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef014e88415ceb970d" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef014e88415ceb970d</id>
			<published>2011-05-05T11:15:41Z</published>
			<updated>2011-05-05T11:15:41Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>Dave Carter</name>
                
			</author>
			<summary>Shared artifacts are also known as models; the best form of understanding of business that I have found yet is...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2009/09/creating-shared-language-and-shared-artiifacts.html">&lt;p&gt;Shared artifacts are also known as models; the best form of understanding of business that I have found yet is when you develop simulators with practitioners. The quality of the the output is only surpassed by the shared understanding created through healthy challenge to the way things actually work.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Christopher Allen commented on &#39;Creating Shared Language and Shared Artifacts&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I&#39;ve not really thought of Shared Language in the context of divisiveness — Shared Language tends to be a function..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2009/09/creating-shared-language-and-shared-artiifacts.html?cid=6a00d8341d8bc053ef0120a5895df3970b#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef0120a5895df3970b" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef0120a5895df3970b</id>
			<published>2009-09-21T21:06:51Z</published>
			<updated>2009-09-21T21:06:51Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>Christopher Allen</name>
                <uri>http://www.LifeWithAlacrity.com</uri>
			</author>
			<summary>I&#39;ve not really thought of Shared Language in the context of divisiveness — Shared Language tends to be a function...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2009/09/creating-shared-language-and-shared-artiifacts.html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve not really thought of Shared Language in the context of divisiveness — Shared Language tends to be a function of small groups. Thus I more think of the divisiveness is coming from the fact that Shared Language typically evolves naturally in a small group, but fails to evolve naturally in larger groups. Possibly a better understanding of how Shared Language and tools to facilitate it like Shared Artifacts function will make it easier for larger groups to grow a Shared Language together. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Julie  Mihalisin commented on &#39;Creating Shared Language and Shared Artifacts&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I&#39;m wondering whether the creation of such language is adding to an intellectual, generational and cultural divisiveness that is already..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2009/09/creating-shared-language-and-shared-artiifacts.html?cid=6a00d8341d8bc053ef0120a5dee57e970c#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef0120a5dee57e970c" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef0120a5dee57e970c</id>
			<published>2009-09-21T17:45:49Z</published>
			<updated>2009-09-21T17:45:49Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>Julie  Mihalisin</name>
                
			</author>
			<summary>I&#39;m wondering whether the creation of such language is adding to an intellectual, generational and cultural divisiveness that is already...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2009/09/creating-shared-language-and-shared-artiifacts.html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m wondering whether the creation of such language is adding to an intellectual, generational and cultural divisiveness that is already prevalent in our society. Can we design tools that serve as bridges? Using the web for social change is a powerful concept, particularly if we can broaden the audience. This is a fascinating topic. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
</feed>

<!-- ph=1 -->
