<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xml:lang="en-us">
	<title>Comments on Collective Choice: Rating Systems</title>
	<subtitle>In our previous article we talked about the many systems available for collective choice. One purpose of our previous article was to create a dictionary of terms for talking about these related, but clearly different, systems. Another was to start offering analyses of these systems, many of which had not been well studied before their introduction onto the Internet. This article provides more in-depth coverage of one of the systems we previously outlined: rating systems. [Post continues]</subtitle>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" title="Comments on Collective Choice: Rating Systems" href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi/comments/atom.xml" />
	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Collective Choice: Rating Systems" href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html"/>
	<generator uri="http://www.typepad.com/">TypePad</generator>
	<xhtml:meta xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="robots" content="noindex" />
	<updated>2005-12-13T01:58:34Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>ChristopherA</name>
		<uri>http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/</uri>
	</author>
	<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi/comments/atom.xml/</id>
    
		<entry>
			<title>thinksketch commented on &#39;Collective Choice: Rating Systems&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I have an interesting brainstorm for you about the netflix challenge: http://www.thinksketchdesign.com/2008/05/03/design/coding/does-the-netflix-challenge-have-it-backwards cheers - thinksketch" href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html?cid=150394777#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef0112791cd6ec28a4" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef0112791cd6ec28a4</id>
			<published>2009-03-04T02:56:13Z</published>
			<updated>2009-03-04T02:56:13Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>thinksketch</name>
                <uri>http://thinksketchdesign.com</uri>
			</author>
			<summary>I have an interesting brainstorm for you about the netflix challenge: http://www.thinksketchdesign.com/2008/05/03/design/coding/does-the-netflix-challenge-have-it-backwards cheers - thinksketch</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html">&lt;p&gt;I have an interesting brainstorm for you about the netflix challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.thinksketchdesign.com/2008/05/03/design/coding/does-the-netflix-challenge-have-it-backwards&lt;br /&gt;
cheers -&lt;br /&gt;
thinksketch&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Brian Hamlin commented on &#39;Collective Choice: Rating Systems&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wow, thorough and cogent. Of all of the points, one missed opportunity occured to me while reading, and that is..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html?cid=17897037#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d834909f0c53ef" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d834909f0c53ef</id>
			<published>2006-05-30T07:43:49Z</published>
			<updated>2007-08-19T11:02:53Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>Brian Hamlin</name>
                
			</author>
			<summary>Wow, thorough and cogent. Of all of the points, one missed opportunity occured to me while reading, and that is...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html">&lt;p&gt;Wow, thorough and cogent. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all of the points, one missed opportunity occured to me while reading, and that is on the EBay statistical validity criticism. The phrase &amp;#39;thus one of the failures for eBay is that it tries to claim meaningfulness for users with very few ratings, where there&amp;#39;s clearly no statistical basis&amp;#39; struck me as off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human transactions are not mechanical actions - they involve situations that often matter. Hence a particular negative may really be cause for serious concern, even if there are not yet many ratings. Also, beginners are not inherantly less important than experienced traders. So though difficult, credit, or blame, is rightly awarded even on the basis of just a few transactions. Exactly how is a subject of further refinement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read some of the EBay dissection papers a while back. This post is far more comprehensive, that is wide ranging, and yet not missing clarity, accuracy or nuance. Master work.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>adrian Chan commented on &#39;Collective Choice: Rating Systems&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good work there, and very thorough. Can we distinguish the social/transactional from the object/informational aspects of a rating situation? I&#39;m..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html?cid=12557538#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d8346ed97953ef" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d8346ed97953ef</id>
			<published>2006-01-04T17:47:53Z</published>
			<updated>2007-08-17T01:46:34Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>adrian Chan</name>
                <uri>http://www.gravity7.com/blog/media/</uri>
			</author>
			<summary>Good work there, and very thorough. Can we distinguish the social/transactional from the object/informational aspects of a rating situation? I&#39;m...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html">&lt;p&gt;Good work there, and very thorough. Can we distinguish the social/transactional from the object/informational aspects of a rating situation? I&amp;#39;m just wondering aloud. On the one hand is the fact that publishing one&amp;#39;s rating of a transaction will reflect on the transaction partner, on oneself, and so is social. On the other hand is the fact one can indeed rate an experience with some objectivity, assuming that the soft stuff has been bracketed out. I dont see how we can bracket out the social though, at least in a way that users will be able to participate in. &lt;br /&gt;
There&amp;#39;s a thing about sincerity as a type of interaction: it&amp;#39;s an attribute of expression that cannot be stated explicitly (say that you&amp;#39;re being sincere and you throw your sincerity into quesion immediately). Ratings may fall into that kind of category of linguistic and metalinguistic acts..&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Seb commented on &#39;Collective Choice: Rating Systems&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Researcher Paul Resnick has been looking at eBay, too. His blog is at http://www.livejournal.com/users/presnick/ and has posts like eBay Live..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html?cid=12406000#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d834a39ae769e2" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d834a39ae769e2</id>
			<published>2005-12-29T13:53:29Z</published>
			<updated>2007-08-17T00:10:14Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>Seb</name>
                <uri>http://seb.notlong.com</uri>
			</author>
			<summary>Researcher Paul Resnick has been looking at eBay, too. His blog is at http://www.livejournal.com/users/presnick/ and has posts like eBay Live...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html">&lt;p&gt;Researcher Paul Resnick has been looking at eBay, too. His blog is at http://www.livejournal.com/users/presnick/ and has posts like eBay Live Trip Report:&lt;br /&gt;
http://www.livejournal.com/users/presnick/8121.html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few relevant articles as well, at http://www.si.umich.edu/~presnick/#publications&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Shally commented on &#39;Collective Choice: Rating Systems&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I find when people give a bad rating on anything from eBay to those hotel and restaurant review sites its..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html?cid=12266237#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d8346d7dbc53ef" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d8346d7dbc53ef</id>
			<published>2005-12-22T00:23:26Z</published>
			<updated>2007-08-16T22:41:19Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>Shally</name>
                <uri>http://www.jobmachine.net/shally/</uri>
			</author>
			<summary>I find when people give a bad rating on anything from eBay to those hotel and restaurant review sites its...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html">&lt;p&gt;I find when people give a bad rating on anything from eBay to those hotel and restaurant review sites its usually as a result of an extremely negative personal experience therefore the rating tends to be exagerated and totally not objective. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blind system like the porposed solution to eBay bilateralism issue is probably best. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been a mystery shopper for a handful of restaurants and the system works quite well. In this system the purpose is to behave exactly like a regular consumer. You sit down, ask about the specials, take mental note of everything from the bathroom sink to the temperature of the food (and a hundred other details), but you don&amp;#39;t behave in any way that would alter the staff you are a mystery shopper (for example writing things down is strickly prohibited).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon returning home you complete a lengthy questionnare about all the details you were supposed to notice. In this system the rewards is for a thorough assesment, regardless of its positive or negative slant. The more detail you provide the better assignments you get next time around. Even if you totally slam a place, but you provide substantial detail, you will be &amp;quot;promoted&amp;quot; to a &amp;quot;bar visit&amp;quot; or something much more rewarding than the typical lunch visit. So, I also agree with this articles suggestion to rate the raters, akin to what Amazon does but without the bias towards volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also addd that there is no middle ground on such ratings. Whether the choices range from Strongly Agree to Strongly Dissagree, or from &amp;quot;shortest wait&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;longest wait&amp;quot; there is no &amp;#39;neutral&amp;#39; choice, nothing is &amp;quot;just right&amp;quot; as in the story about the three bears and the porridge. Even with numerical choices they are always even, not odd, so there is not chance of ranking in the middle. I like that. I think it pushes you to be more realistic. Having a middle ground leaves the undecided the opportunity to not make a decision. A &amp;quot;middle&amp;quot; rating is of no use to anyone. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>F. Randall Farmer commented on &#39;Collective Choice: Rating Systems&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An interesting point missing from this good summary: Many huge ratings sites see a clear bimodal distribution of scores when..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html?cid=12107756#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d834a2582769e2" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d834a2582769e2</id>
			<published>2005-12-15T00:13:25Z</published>
			<updated>2007-08-16T20:46:41Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>F. Randall Farmer</name>
                <uri>http://www.fudco.com/habitat</uri>
			</author>
			<summary>An interesting point missing from this good summary: Many huge ratings sites see a clear bimodal distribution of scores when...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html">&lt;p&gt;An interesting point missing from this good summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many huge ratings sites see a clear bimodal distribution of scores when rating products(movies, cds, books, etc.)  with a simple scoring scheme, such as a single 5-star scale: The nodes are at 1 and 5 stars, with the love-or-hate scores making up more than 80% of all scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, some of that is a function of the intrinsic cost vs. incentive structures of completing ratings and reviews. When there is a clear direct benifit to the user (such as Netflix, Slashdot, or Yahoo! Music&amp;#39;s Launchcast) ratings tend to distribute a bit more evenly (but just a bit.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point is that the actual end-user application of the rating has a large effect on the nature of the scores that will be created.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Brad Templeton commented on &#39;Collective Choice: Rating Systems&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It&#39;s rarely used, but asking people to rank from -5 to +5 can be better than ranking from 0 to..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html?cid=12071623#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d8346cc1dc53ef" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d8346cc1dc53ef</id>
			<published>2005-12-13T21:11:31Z</published>
			<updated>2007-08-16T20:21:05Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>Brad Templeton</name>
                <uri>http://ideas.4brad.com</uri>
			</author>
			<summary>It&#39;s rarely used, but asking people to rank from -5 to +5 can be better than ranking from 0 to...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s rarely used, but asking people to rank from -5 to +5 can be better than ranking from 0 to 10.   You make it very clear that &amp;quot;0&amp;quot; means average/neutral.   You won&amp;#39;t entirely eliminate the positive bias in ratings but you can reduce it.  And you bring everybody closer to the same mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve concluded over time that in fact the response to a negative feedback on eBay should be disabled, as it contains no information.   Who, after all, is going to give a positive feedback to somebody after they have slapped a negative on you?  The likely choices there are no-feedback or neutral from a charitable person and of course a revenge negative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So they could make it simpler.  If the first person gives a negative, the transaction is considered sour.  In your stats it would list the number of first-negatives you left for others.  (The number of negs you leave for others is already visible but harder to find.)  Ideally split buyer/seller.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Kalle commented on &#39;Collective Choice: Rating Systems&#39;</title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I&#39;ve ran into my fair share of voting systems, but by far the worst I&#39;ve ever seen is the one..." href="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html?cid=12065974#comment-6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d834a23cd369e2" />
			<id>tag:typepad.com,2003:6a00d8341d8bc053ef00d834a23cd369e2</id>
			<published>2005-12-13T18:42:58Z</published>
			<updated>2007-08-16T20:16:28Z</updated>
			<author>
				<name>Kalle</name>
                <uri>http://www.livejournal.com/userinfo.bml?user=kallewooof</uri>
			</author>
			<summary>I&#39;ve ran into my fair share of voting systems, but by far the worst I&#39;ve ever seen is the one...</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.lifewithalacrity.com/2005/12/collective_choi.html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve ran into my fair share of voting systems, but by far the worst I&amp;#39;ve ever seen is the one used at www.animenfo.com, a database of anime products with user ratings. When giving a product a rating, a user is required to also write a constructive review on the product. However, the reviews are moderated and, often, removed from the database as &amp;quot;unconstructive&amp;quot; by the limited number of moderators. The problem with this approach is that the moderators are inevitably biased. A submitted, bad rating on a product, if reviewed by a moderator who personally likes the show being rated, is often removed from the database with the claim that the review was not constructive. Perhaps not entirely related, but an example of ratings-gone-awry, all the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Kalle.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		</entry>
	
</feed>

<!-- ph=1 -->
